<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Robotics - Category - My personal Blog</title>
        <link>https://leonkie.github.io/categories/robotics/</link>
        <description>Robotics - Category - My personal Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leon@kiesgen.eu (Leon Kie)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>leon@kiesgen.eu (Leon Kie)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonkie.github.io/categories/robotics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Wearable Compact Shoulder Exoskeleton</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/wearable_compact_shoulderexoskeletion/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/wearable_compact_shoulderexoskeletion/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the realm of biomedical engineering, my Master&rsquo;s thesis at the Technical University of Munich&rsquo;s Institute of Micro Technology and Medical Device Technology (MiMed) introduces a novel approach to shoulder rehabilitation through the development of the Actuated Scissor Shoulder Mechanism Exoskeleton (ASSM-EXO). This project contributtes to the development in the field of mobile exoskeletions, focusing on the design and evaluation of a compact, wearable device intended to aid in the recovery of individuals experiencing shoulder mobility impairments, particularly following stroke-related hemiparesis.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Anthropomorphic Prosthesis for the Cybathlon Challenge</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/anthropomorphic_hand/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/anthropomorphic_hand/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction to the Cybathlon Prosthesis In the course of 2 Semesters, we, in a team of 3 people, designed and prototyped a robotic hand for the Cybathlon competition, aiming to realise an anthropomorphic prosthetic hand. The project was guided by the principle of anthropomorphism in robotics, focusing on emulating the appearance, motion, and sensory capabilities of the human hand. This approach led us to develop a prosthesis that not only met the functional requirements of the competition but also had a visually appealing, human-like design.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
