<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - My personal Blog</title>
        <link>https://leonkie.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | My personal Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leon@kiesgen.eu (Leon Kie)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>leon@kiesgen.eu (Leon Kie)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonkie.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Reverse Engineering a Old Bus Display - Flipdot Lawo 28x16</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/flip_dot_display/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/flip_dot_display/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is a Flipdot Display ? A flipdot display is a fascinating example of electromechanical display technology, often found on old buses as destination signs. These displays are valued for their retro aesthetics and functional reliability. Each dot in the display is a magnetic disc with one coloured side and one black side. The disc is flipped using an electromagnetic coil which holds the disc in place by magnetic polarisation.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Wearable Compact Shoulder Exoskeleton</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/wearable_compact_shoulderexoskeletion/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/wearable_compact_shoulderexoskeletion/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the realm of biomedical engineering, my Master&rsquo;s thesis at the Technical University of Munich&rsquo;s Institute of Micro Technology and Medical Device Technology (MiMed) introduces a novel approach to shoulder rehabilitation through the development of the Actuated Scissor Shoulder Mechanism Exoskeleton (ASSM-EXO). This project contributtes to the development in the field of mobile exoskeletions, focusing on the design and evaluation of a compact, wearable device intended to aid in the recovery of individuals experiencing shoulder mobility impairments, particularly following stroke-related hemiparesis.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Anthropomorphic Prosthesis for the Cybathlon Challenge</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/anthropomorphic_hand/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/anthropomorphic_hand/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction to the Cybathlon Prosthesis In the course of 2 Semesters, we, in a team of 3 people, designed and prototyped a robotic hand for the Cybathlon competition, aiming to realise an anthropomorphic prosthetic hand. The project was guided by the principle of anthropomorphism in robotics, focusing on emulating the appearance, motion, and sensory capabilities of the human hand. This approach led us to develop a prosthesis that not only met the functional requirements of the competition but also had a visually appealing, human-like design.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Occupancy munich - Avoid people in corona times</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/occupancy_munich/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/occupancy_munich/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[George_OrwellBig brother is watching youWeekly overview of the occupancy of a facility Website (No longer maintained) Introduction I am a climber and I like to go climbing gyms or bouldering gyms. As I and a friend were going regularly to the same gym in Munich, we kept discussing the best possible time we could meet and encounter as few other people as possible. When we had the reluctance to choose our arrival time freely this wasn&rsquo;t a big deal.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Inverted Pendulum, which is also a Lamp</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/inverted_pendolum/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 23:38:56 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/inverted_pendolum/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction The inverted pendulum is one of the most popular demonstrations in system control, has been studied since the 19601 and is a prime example at unis and other research institutes. However, the inverted pendulum, which is nothing more than a pendulum that has the centre of mass above the pivot point, yet has no particular use case. To change this once in for all, I build an inverted pendulum lamp, which can be used as a normal stylish desk lamp.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Building my custom Oak Hangboard</title>
    <link>https://leonkie.github.io/hangboard/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://leonkie.github.io/hangboard/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[For those who share a passion for climbing, a personalized hangboard is more than a training tool; I took on the challenge of creating a custom hangboard from the ground up, and here&rsquo;s how I turned oak wood leftovers into my dream hangboard and also a present for a friend.
Choosing the Right Wood and Finger Pocket Layout The journey began with selecting the perfect wood. I sourced oak hardwood leftovers from a nearby sawmill, known for its strength and durability—essential qualities for a hangboard even when undergoing high intensity training sessions.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
